Finding Aid for the Hugo Ballin Papers LSC.0407
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hugo Ballin papers
1890-1956
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ballin, Hugo
LSC.0407
13.0 Linear Feet (27 document boxes and 6 oversize boxes)
Hugo Ballin (1879-1956) was born in New York City. He began his Hollywood career creating motion picture sets for Samuel Goldwyn and later worked as a director and producer. He ultimately gave up his film career to focus on art and writing. The collection consists of original paintings and drawings by Ballin, correspondence, literary manuscripts, books, clippings, and photographs.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994622813606533
Biography
Hugo Ballin was born March 7, 1879 in New York City. He attended the Art Students League in New York, spent several years traveling and studying in Italy, and became a portrait painter. In 1917, he began working as an art director for Goldwyn Pictures and subsequently moved to California in 1921. In the 1920s, he began writing, producing, and directing films, and formed his own production company, Hugo Ballin Productions, Inc. Ballin's wife, actress Mabel Croft Ballin, was featured in his silent film adaptations of literary classics, such as Jane Eyre (1921) and Vanity Fair (1923). With the advent of talking pictures, Ballin retired from film to focus on painting and writing. As a noted muralist, he completed a number of significant commissioned works across the country during the course of his career, including murals at the Griffith Observatory in Los Angeles and at the State Capitol in Madison, Wisconsin. He designed a seventeen-foot medallion of Pallas Athena which hung over the entrance to the 1932 Olympics in Los Angeles. He also published several novels, including The Woman at the Door (1925), Stigma (1928), and Dolce Far Niente (1933). Ballin was a member of the National Institute of Arts and Letters and the National Academy of Design. He lived in Pacific Palisades until he died in 1956.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, literary manuscripts, books, scrapbooks, and photographs of Hugo and Mabel Ballin and their family, friends, and residence. Also contains original paintings and drawings, including sketches and watercolors by Ballin. Correspondents include Walter Winchell, Louis B. Mayer, Booker T. Washington, Edward G. Robinson, Paul Jordan-Smith, Oscar Straus, Gloria Swanson, Louis Untermeyer, Lionel Barrymore, Joan Crawford, Walter Damrosch, Samuel Goldwyn, Helen Keller, David O. Selznick, Darryl F. Zanuck, Erich W. Korngold, Howard Pyle, Walt Disney, Royal Cortissoz, John C. Austin, William Goetz, Harry Rapf, William Wendt, Robert Brackman, George Elmer Browne, Lydia Field Emmet, Edmund Tarbell, Ernest Lawson, Albert Sterner, William J. Baer, Fredrick Dana Marsh, Howard Giles, Frederick Ballard Williams, Ivan Olinsky, Hobart Nichols, DeWitt Lockman, Daniel Garber, John Fabian Carlson, Charles Rosen, Jonas Lie, Guy Wiggins, Frederick Waugh, Barry Faulkner, Cecilia Beaux, Maxfield Parrish, Harry Watrous, Edward Hopper, Edward Bruce, Umberto Romano, Clarence H. Carter, Ernest L. Blumenschein, Jerome Myers, Dean Cornwell, Leon Kroll, Arthur Hopkins, Abraham Lehr, and Arthur Stringer.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Literary manuscripts (Boxes 1-13).
Artwork by Hugo Ballin (Boxes 14, 26, 31-33).
Photographs (Boxes 15-20, 26-28, 31).
Ephemera (Boxes 21-23, 25, 29-30).
Correspondence (Boxes 24-25).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Hugo Ballin Papers (3 items).
Motion picture art directors -- United States -- Archives.; American fiction -- 20th century -- Archives.; Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Ballin, Hugo, 1879-1956--Archives.
- Artwork by Hugo Ballin (Box 14, 26, 31-33)
  Scope and Content
  Drawings, sketches, and watercolors by Hugo Ballin, including early work. Also includes one engraver's plate of Ballin painting.
  - Christmas Stories, 1950. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Draft of illustrated book.
  - Sketches, drawings and watercolor paintings, including many early works, ca. 1899-1944.; 24 pieces. In folder. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Includes drafts of illustrated book covers.
  - Sketches, drawings and watercolor paintings, including many early works, ca. 1887-1950.; 75 pieces. In folder. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Early watercolor paintings, ca. 1885-1896.; 6 pieces. In envelope. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Large sketchbook. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Drawings and studies for murals by Hugo Ballin. v.p., v.d.; 13 items. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Studies for murals. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Done with pencil and paint.
  - Pencil drawings pertaining to murals. (Box 31, Folder 2-11)
    Primarily pencil drawings on mat board, likely drafts of mural panels. Some of the pencil drawings have been colored with watercolors.
    - Travel by covered wagon. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - The bull of Alexander VI dividing the New World between Spain and Portugal / Sir Francis Drake -- San Francisco Bay, July 1578. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Mariano Guadalupe / San Francisco's first schoolhouse / Discovery of gold / Frontiersman. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Saint Francis / Father Crespi / Fages with twelve soldiers and two servants on their march toward where San Francisco now stands -- March 22, 1772. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Panama-Pacific Exposition, 1915. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - East side of Plaza San Francisco, 1849. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - A mission father enters California. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Transportation. (Box 31, Folder 9)
      "Pilots -- DC-3 plane / The Grumman JF-2 of the U.S. coast guard / Airport operator - giving local conditions / Archytas -- 4 c. B.C. flying a wooden dove."
    - Overland stage arrives -- 1860., Damaged -- right side is missing portion of the drawing and mat board. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Vigilance Committee's hanging Hetherington & Brace -- July 29, 1856. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Xth Olympiad diploma, 1932. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    Diploma addressed to Hugo Ballin for his activity as a member of the Advisory Committee on Preparations for the Xth Olympiad in Los Angeles, 1932.
  - Untitled landscape painting (1 of 2)., Right side of mat board is damaged but painting is unharmed. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Untitled landscape painting (2 of 2)., Right side of mat board is damaged but painting is unharmed. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Includes drawings from Ballin's childhood.
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Watercolors and drawings. v.p., v.d.; 18 pieces. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Watercolors and drawings. v.p., v.d.; 13 pieces. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Sketches. v.p., v.d.; Sketchbook and 8 loose pieces in an envelope. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Engraver's plate of Ballin painting. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Sketches and photographs pertaining to murals. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    Includes annotated sketches relating to mural work, several photographs of murals and Mabel Ballin, and four negatives of Milton Getz residence murals.
  - Set design drawings. (Box 33, Folder 1-37)
    Set and production design drawings for an unidentified film, each depicting a different scene. Pencil and charcoal drawings on paper.
    - Scene 94. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      "Office of Amalgamated Oil Co."
    - Scene 190. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      "Buck's room in hotel."
    - Introduction no. 2. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Scene 36. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      "Tom."
    - Scene 59. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Untitled. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Scene 218. (Box 33, Folder 7)
      "1st sketch for Jai Mahal at Juhu Beach."
    - Scene 59. (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Second drawing by this title although images are quite different.
    - Introduction no. 1. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Scene 87. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Introduction no. 1. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Scene 250. (Box 33, Folder 12)
      "Bill and Baroness leaving Bombay."
    - Scene 248. (Box 33, Folder 13)
      "Taj Mahal Bar. Buck and Bill."
    - Bedroom in the Jai Mahal. (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Scene 39. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Scene 249. (Box 33, Folder 16)
      "Bill leaving Bombay."
    - Scene 191. (Box 33, Folder 17)
      "Carol thinks of her remote Lutheran childhood in America."
    - Scene 218. (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Ali (after operation). (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Introduction no. 2. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Scene 159. (Box 33, Folder 21)
      "Buck's room at the Institute of Tropical Diseases, Bill sees his old friend."
    - Scene 167. (Box 33, Folder 22)
      "The little curtained room of Rama. Mrs. Trollope and Rama."
    - Scene 82. (Box 33, Folder 23)
      "Mr. Snodgrass."
    - Scene 97. (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Scene 76. (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Scene 114. (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Scene 93. (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Scene 118 b. (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Scene 218. (Box 33, Folder 29)
      "Dancers at the Jai Mahal."
    - Scene 124. (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - The Maharani of Chandragar. (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Scene 51. (Box 33, Folder 32)
      "Carol opens her jewel case."
    - Scene 175. (Box 33, Folder 33)
      "Some adagio dancers."
    - Scene 120. (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Scene 218. (Box 33, Folder 35)
      "Dancers at the Jai Mahal." Second drawing by this title although images are different.
    - Scene 172. (Box 33, Folder 36)
      "A cheap restaurant and night club."
    - Scene 81. (Box 33, Folder 37)
- Photographs (Box 15-20, 26-28, 31)
  Photographs of Hugo and Mabel Ballin, family, friends, residences, and pertaining to murals and paintings by Hugo Ballin.
  - Album containing early photographs of Hugo Ballin's family and friends. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Murals at Griffith Park Observatory, ca. 1934. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Murals at the Milton Getz House in Beverly Hills. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Ballin's murals and paintings. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Hugo Ballin, family, friends, and residences, ca. 1927-1950. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Mausoleum murals. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Includes both prints and negatives.
  - Scrapbook of mural paintings by Ballin. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Early photographs of Hugo Ballin and family., In an envelope. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Mabel Ballin, mostly movie stills., In an envelope. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Hugo Ballin is shown directing Mabel Ballin in several photographs.
  - Hugo Ballin, friends, relatives, and residences (folder 1 of 2)., In an envelope. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Hugo Ballin, friends, relatives, and residences (folder 2 of 2)., In an envelope. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Mabel Ballin. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    One photograph in a folder; taken by Hugo Ballin.
  - Murals and paintings by Hugo Ballin (folder 1 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Murals and paintings by Hugo Ballin (folder 2 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Negatives of murals and paintings by Hugo Ballin. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Ballin with his work. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Includes some photographs from Ballin's youth.
  - Movie stills and portraits of Mabel Ballin., Scrapbook. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 1 of 6)., Scrapbook. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 2 of 6)., Loose photographs in a folder. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 3 of 6)., Scrapbook. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 4 of 6)., Scrapbook. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 5 of 6)., Scrapbook. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Movie stills of Mabel Ballin (folder 6 of 6)., Scrapbook. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Hugo Ballin., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Mounted portrait of Hugo Ballin.
  - National Academy group portrait., ca. 1909. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Photograph at National Academy of Design with names of subjects noted (including Hugo Ballin).
  - Mabel Ballin., 2 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of and pertaining to murals by Ballin., Folder 4 includes a small envelope containing loose photographs. (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
    Most photographs appear to have been taken at Ballin's residence, and Ballin is in many of them. A majority of the photographs are mounted on scrapbook pages.
  - Portraits of Hugo Ballin. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Portraits and movie stills of Mabel Ballin. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Photograph album. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains mostly pictures of the Ballin residence and of murals by Hugo Ballin.
  - Mabel Ballin., Approximately 140 pieces. (Box 28)
    Box is full of large prints, mostly stills from movie scenes with some portraits.
  - Hugo Ballin's artwork. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Includes both murals and portraits.
  - Mabel Ballin in costumes. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Also includes a few negatives and some photographs of Hugo Ballin and his work taken at the Ballin residence.
  - Ballin's artwork. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Includes murals at Los Angeles County Hospital.
  - Studies and finished artwork., ca. 1905-1909. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Paintings by Hugo Ballin. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Sketches and paintings. (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Ephemera (Box 21-23, 25, 29-30)
  Books, press clippings, brochures, and pamphlets containing material pertaining to Hugo and Mabel Ballin.
  - Newspaper clippings relating to Hugo and Mabel Ballin, ca. 1919-1922. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Magazine clippings relating to Hugo and Mabel Ballin, ca. 1921-1925. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings relating to Hugo and Mabel Ballin (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1919-1926. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings relating to Hugo and Mabel Ballin (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1922-1925. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings relating to Hugo and Mabel Ballin (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1921-1926. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Griffith Observer magazine, 1939 March. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Hugo Ballin's mural is on the cover of the magazine.
  - Two issues of large promotional magazine for Ballin's film adaptation of Vanity Fair, ca. 1923. (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, memorabilia, and miscellaneous publications pertaining to Hugo and Mabel Ballin, ca. 1917-1922. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, memorabilia, and miscellaneous publications pertaining to Hugo and Mabel Ballin, ca. 1921-1947. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, memorabilia, and miscellaneous publications pertaining to Hugo and Mabel Ballin, ca. 1909-1951. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Social Service Review magazine, 1944 October. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    This magazine issue features an article by Hugo Ballin.
  - Olympic Games Official Pictorial Souvenir, 1932. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Mrs. Claus goes shopping by Hugo Ballin, 1941 December. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Article in Evening Outlook newspaper written and illustrated by Ballin. In an envelope.
  - Guilfoyle, J.M. How to Remember or The Secret and Art of Memory Reduced to a System. Chicago: W.J. Jefferson Printing and Publishing Co., 1897. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Art Institute of Chicago. Catalogue of the Twenty-Eighth Annual Exhibition of American Oil Paintings and Sculpture, ca. 1915. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Baker, George M. Down by the Sea. Boston: George M. Baker & Co., 1876. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Wylie, John Edward. Snowed In. New York: Samuel French & Son, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Words, Prefixes and Suffixes, with Latin & Greek Roots in Common Use. New York: J.S. Babcock, 1888. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sansone, Anthony J. Rhythm. Brooklyn, NY, 1935. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Promotional campaign book for Ballin's film adaptation of Jane Eyre, ca. 1921. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Promotional campaign book for Ballin's film adaptation of East Lynne, ca. 1921. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Magazine advertisement for Married People starring Mabel Ballin. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Lehmann, Liza. Four Cautionary Tales and a Moral. London: Chappell & Co., 1910. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Words by H. Belloc; music by Liza Lehmann.
  - Unit Operating Agreement (Under Iniskin Peninsula Unit Agreement), 1953 July. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Unit Agreement for the Development and Operation of the Iniskin Peninsula Unit Area, 1953 July. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Mural paintings by Hugo Ballin. New York: Privately printed, 1913.; 3 copies. (Box 23, Folder 13-15)
  - "Over 65" by Hugo Ballin. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    Reproduction of article written by Hugo Ballin.
  - Utagawa, Kuniyoshi. Taiheiki Eiyuden, 1867. (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Illustrated book of Japanese ukiyo-e prints given to Hugo Ballin as a gift.
  - Publicity information for Jane Eyre, ca. 1921.; 2 items in an envelope. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Includes published samples of Ballin's artwork, newspaper clippings, and mementos.
  - Scrapbook of press clippings of Mabel and Hugo Ballin; mostly reviews, 1927-1940. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of press clippings of Hugo Ballin, 1905-1918. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Pertains primarily to his early art and film career.
  - Scrapbook of press clippings. (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (Box 24, Box 25)
  Letters to Hugo Ballin.
  - Letters to Hugo Ballin, 1900-1939. (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1939. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Pertains to art and film career and includes many letters from American artists (particularly American Impressionists). Notable correspondents include: John C. Austin, William Goetz, Harry Rapf, William Wendt, Robert Brackman, George Elmer Browne, Lydia Field Emmet, Edmund Tarbell, Ernest Lawson, Albert Sterner, William J. Baer, Fredrick Dana Marsh, Howard Giles, Frederick Ballard Williams, Ivan Olinsky, Hobart Nichols, DeWitt Lockman, Daniel Garber, John Fabian Carlson, Charles Rosen, Jonas Lie, Guy Wiggins, Frederick Waugh, Barry Faulkner, Cecilia Beaux, Maxfield Parrish, Harry Watrous, Edward Hopper, Edward Bruce, Umberto Romano, Clarence H. Carter, Ernest L. Blumenschein, Jerome Myers, Dean Cornwell, Leon Kroll, Arthur Hopkins, Abraham Lehr, Arthur Stringer.
    - Correspondence, 1933-1935. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Pertains to commissioned murals and public art works. Includes correspondence from Ballin's lawyers, the National Society of Mural Painters, and Edward Bruce of the National Works of Art Project.
    - Correspondence, 1930-1932. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Pertains to commissioned murals and the activities of the Huntington Palisades Property Owners Corporation Ltd. Notable correspondents include Cass Gilbert and Royal Cortissoz.
    - Correspondence, 1920-1929. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Primarily related to financial and business matters, including film projects, residences, taxes, interactions with Goldwyn Pictures, and Hugo Ballin Productions, Inc. Notable correspondents include the Goldwyn Pictures Corporation and Louis Joseph Vance.
    - Correspondence, 1910-1920. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Pertains primarily to Ballin's early film career. Includes contract with Goldwyn Pictures Corporation.
    - Correspondence, 1900-1909. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      Pertains to travels abroad and early art career. A number of items are in Italian. Notable correspondents include Jules Guerin and William T. Evans.
  - Letters to Hugo Ballin, 1940-1956. (Box 25)
    - One folder of letters from the following well-known people:, 64 pieces.; Walter Winchell, Anita Loos, Louis B. Mayer, Booker Taliaferro Washington, Rose Cecil O'Neill, Edward G. Robinson, Cornelia Otis Skinner, Paul Jordan-Smith, Oscar Straus, Gloria Swanson, Deems Taylor, Henry Major Tomlinson, Louis Untermeyer, Harley Granville-Barker, Lionel Barrymore, Rex Ellingwood Beach, Louis Bromfield, Robert William Chambers, Joan Crawford, Walter Damrosch, Maxine Elliott, Mary Garden, Samuel Goldwyn, Jean Hersholt, Helen Keller, David Selznick, Darryl Zanuck, Erich Korngold, Robert Blum, Howard Pyle, Walt Disney, Rockwell Kent, Millard Sheets, Reginald Marsh. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      General note
      These names are all added entries in Special Collections public card catalog.
    - Correspondence, 1940-1949. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Pertains to art career and friendships with artists, patrons, and critics. Notable correspondents include: Charles C. Curran, Samuel T. Shaw, Dean Cornwell, DeWitt Parshall, Harrison S. Morris, Hobart Nichols, Royal Cortissoz, Iris Barry, Edward Alden Jewell, S.J. Woolf, and Leon Kroll.
    - Correspondence, 1950-1959. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Includes information pertaining to publication attempts and Iniskin Bay project. Notable correspondents include: Charles Keck, S. Seymour Thomas, Lee de Forest, Faith Baldwin, Ivan Le Lorraine Albright, Bertha Klausner.
    - Correspondence, In accordion folder. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Includes letters, notes, manuscript drafts, some sketches, and some ephemera.
    - Correspondence with Lucien Cailliet, ca. 1952. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Pertains to Poor Richard, which featured lyrics by Hugo Ballin and music by Lucien Cailliet. Includes score.
- Literary Manuscripts (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13)
  Screenplays and novels written by Hugo Ballin, including both drafts and published works. Also includes drafts of Ballin's memoirs, entitled I'll Be Damned.
  - Lovers in Flight., Typescript. In black, paper binder. 85pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Small, ink sketches interspersed on loose slips of paper.
  - Lovers in Flight., Typescript (carbon) with minor corrections. 85pp. In grey, paper binder. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    First leaf has press clipping pasted in, which reads: Ballin writes of ant life.
    Also: 2 more copies with slight variations.
  - Lovers in Flight., Typescript (carbon) with minor corrections. 85pp. In grey, paper binder. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lovers in Flight., Typescript (carbon) with minor corrections. 83pp. In orange, paper binder. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Refuge., Typescript, 135pp. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resa of Night Lights, by R. Cleaden [pseudonym], 1923.; Typescript (carbon), 17pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - River Song, by W. Croft [pseudonym]., Outline with sketches in color. 44pp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Song of the River., Typescript (carbon). 20pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Shiksa, by Abigail Cohen [pseudonym]., Typescript. 113pp., in black, loose-leaf notebook. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Shiksa., Typescript (carbon). 113pp. In tan, paper binder. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sixty-Six North Wind., Typescript with sketches for set designs. 21pp. In folder. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Written for television...never submitted to any producer or agent/H.B.
  - Under the Stars, or, Waiting. New York City, 1924.; Typescript (carbon). 37pp. In blue, paper cover. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - War Wife., 80pp. In rust colored paper binder. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    A short synopsis composed primarily of pages of rough sketches in pencil and color, with pages of typescript interspersed.
  - Skull and Bones., Typescript (carbon) with holograph corrections. 278pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Title The Damned Dr. Blake crossed out.
  - The Damned Dr. Blake, by Seargeant B. Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript (carbon) with corrections. 287pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Illustration of Dr. Blake on first leaf.